Guide to the Division of Community Education videotapes, 1950-1991
Division of Community Education videotapes
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Division of Community Education videotapes, 1950-1991 (bulk 1950-1965)
6800
Puerto Rico.División de Educación de la Comunidad.
circa 42 videotapes.
Movie Film
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Videotapes of films made by the Division of Community Education, many of them directed by Jack Delano. Some are documentaries on current developments in Puerto Rican performing and visual arts; others are evidently fictional.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
The División de Educación de la Comunidad (DIVEDCO) was created within the Dept. of Education of Puerto Rico in 1949.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Videotapes of films made by the Division of Community Education, many of them directed by Jack Delano. Some are documentaries on current developments in Puerto Rican performing and visual arts; others are evidently fictional.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Puerto Rico.; Delano, Jack.
Subjects:
Public television--Puerto Rico.; Art, Modern--Puerto Rico.
Places:
Puerto Rico--Intellectual life.
Form and Genre Terms:
Videotapes.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Botija, La, 1964; V-1043 (Box 1)
- Buena Herencia, La, 1965; V-1039 (Box 1)
- Buena Herencia, La, 1965; V-1040 (Box 1)
- Cacique, El, 1957; V-1042 (Box 1)
- Casa de un Amigo, La, 1963; V-1041 (Box 1)
- Contemplado, El, 1957; V-1044 (Box 1)
- Cuando los Padres Olvidan, 1961; V-1056 (Box 1)
  Also available on DVD #503
- Danza Puertorriqueña, 1952; V-1046 (Box 1)
- De los Cuatro Cabos Blancos, El, 1957; V-1045 (Box 1)
- Desde las Nubes, 1950; V-1047 (Box 1)
- Desde las Nubes, 1950; V-1048 (Box 1)
- Doña Julia, 1955; V-1049 (Box 1)
- Experanza, La, 1964; V-1056 (Box 1)
- Festival de Navidad, n.d.; V-1050 (Box 1)
- Gallo Pelón, El, 1961; V-1050 (Box 1)
- Geña la de Blas, 1964; V-1051 (Box 1)
- Geña la de Blas, 1964; V-1052 (Box 1)
- Gota de Agua, Una, 1949; V-1043 (Box 1)
- Guardarraya, La, 1964; V-1053 (Box 1)
- Ignacio, 1956; V-1954 (Box 1)
- Juan sin Seso, 1959; V-1055 (Box 1)
- Leche, La, n.d.; V-1056 (Box 1)
- Manos del Hombre, Las, 1953; V-1057 (Box 1)
  Also available on DVD #504
- Mayo Florido, 1958; V-1058 (Box 1)
- Modesta, 1956; V-1059 (Box 1)
- Modesta, 1956; V-1060 (Box 1)
- Nenen de la Ruta Mora, 1955; V-1061 (Box 1)
- Nosotros Tenemos Derecho, 1960; V-1062 (Box 1)
  Also available on DVD #505
- Noticiero (comedores escolares), V-1056 (Box 1)
- Nueva Escuela Santa Olaya en Bayamón, Una, n.d.; V-1050 (Box 1)
- Pablo Casals en Puerto Rico, 1956; V-1050 (Box 1)
- Parranda Campesina, 1958; V-1063 (Box 1)
- Pedacito de Tierra, 1952; V-1043 (Box 1)
- Pedacito de Tierra, 1952; V-1064 (Box 1)
- Peloteros, Los (sound only), 1991; V-1065 (Box 1)
- Peloteros, Los (sound only), 1991; V-1067 (Box 1)
- Peloteros, Los (visual only), 1991; V-1066 (Box 1)
- Puente, El, 1954; V-1069 (Box 1)
- Puente, El, 1954; V-1068 (Box 1)
- Puerto Rico: Art and Identity, 1991; V-1070 (Box 1)
- Que Opina la Mujer, 1957; V-1043 (Box 1)
- Quiebra, La, 1965; V-1079 (Box 1)
- Resplandor, El, 1961; V-1071 (Box 1)
- Romance Musical, 1958; V-1072 (Box 1)
- Ronda Incompleta, La, 1966; V-1073 (Box 1)
- Santero, El, 1956; V-1074 (Box 1)
- Secreto, El, 1958; V-1075 (Box 1)
- Secreto, El, 1958; V-1076 (Box 1)
- Serenata, 1965; V-1077 (Box 1)
- Voz en la Montaña, Una, 1952; V-1078 (Box 1)
- Yugo, El, 1959; V-1056 (Box 1)
- Yugo, El, 1959; V-1080 (Box 1)